# **Sharmila Jaideep**

Sharmila.jaideep@gmail.com | +91 8939811688 | Chennai, India.

#### PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

With more than 20 years of experience in the field of learning and development, I have extensive expertise in the complete training life cycle. This includes actively managing stakeholders and customers, creating and implementing competency-based training programs (capability building), managing and developing training solutions, performing training needs analysis, evaluating the ROI derived from training efforts, commercializing training solutions (external offer), and managing development and delivery teams (global). Furthermore, I possess expertise in knowledge management.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Schneider Electric Systems India

Jan 2012- July 2023

#### GM - Knowledge Management Content and Communities

Apr 2022 - July 2023

- Creating and implementing a comprehensive KM strategy aligned with the organization's goals and objectives.
- Designing and establishing the processes and systems necessary for capturing, organizing, storing, and retrieving knowledge.
- Managing the processes and initiatives to capture and share knowledge across the organization, including promoting a knowledge-sharing culture, encouraging employees to document and share their expertise, and facilitating the creation of communities of practice/knowledge-sharing forums.
- Conducting training sessions for KM champs from countries and providing ongoing support to KM
  Champs and users of knowledge management tools and systems.
- Establishing metrics and measures to assess the effectiveness of knowledge management initiatives, identifying areas of improvement, and making data-driven decisions.
- Establishing and maintaining Technical Skills and Knowledge (TS&K) of the delivery and service organizations (global) by working closely with the delivery directors and HR business partners from the regions.
- Identifying skills gaps at regular intervals and imparting the right skills and competencies to ensure customer satisfaction.

- Developed and implemented learning and development strategies aligned with the organization's goals and objectives.
- Developed and executed the commercial work streams to achieve growth and profitability goals for the business unit, across APAC, EMEA, and Americas regions.
- Developed and implemented innovative digital training products and services.
- Led the creation and implementation of capability and development strategies and activities within the People function to support the learning needs.
- Led the consulting function to measure and improve customer intimacy, satisfaction, and service quality across APAC, EMEA, and the Americas regions.
- Developed operational strategies in collaboration with regional delivery and services leaders to define and achieve annual efficiency targets through internal and external training solutions.
- Conceptualized and implemented a framework that transforms employee development initiatives into a holistic, end-to-end, connected-and-continuous process enabled by digitization.
- Managed the course development function tasked to develop technical training courses and assessments using the Agile development methodology.
- Managed trainer schedules from various regions.

## Senior Manager - Learning Solutions and Services

Jan 2012 - Mar 2018

- Built and managed a high-performing learning and development team.
- Established annual workplan for training development and delivery.
- Developed, administered, and delivered training programs based on regional requirements.
- Managed the development, revisions, and translations of eLearning & classroom courses.
- Reported efficiency savings through learning solutions to the top management.
- Built a customizable onboarding program based on the business needs of the internal and external audience.
- Managed, supervised, and developed training development staff located in different regions (selection, appointment, separation).
- Conducted midyear and yearly employee performance evaluations.
- Developed and maintained process improvement processes and standards documentation to ensure a global standard.
- Identified and managed vendors/contractors.
- Developed design documents based on TNA.
- Developed training solutions using authoring tools.

#### **Everonn Medical Education Ltd.**

# **Head Content Development**

Jan 2011 - Dec 2011

- Undertook market research and evaluated the existing skills available in the medical field.
- Prepared recommendations to address the skill gap in the nursing and allied health industry.
- Provided innovation and best-in-class training solutions.
- Identified and collaborated with the content developers and SMEs on a template and structure for nursing, allied health, nursing, and fellowship curriculum.
- Evaluated all content design and development with the content developer and SME peer group and made recommendations for improvement.
- Established standardized development processes and procedures.
- Built and managed a high-performing team.

# **Expertus Private Ltd.**

#### Manager - Instructional Design

Feb 2008 - Nov 2010

- Assisted and conducted training needs analysis and training gap analysis.
- Defined project scope, identified project deliverables, and created project plans.
- Identified innovative Instructional Design solutions.
- Developed and reviewed design documents containing instructional strategy, content structure, assessment strategy, and storyboards.
- Managed and maintained the competency level of the Instructional Design team.
- Developed instructional/storyboard templates.
- Provided coaching and support to fresh recruits as and when required.
- Assisted in creating proposals.

# Satyam Computer Services Ltd.

# Senior Interaction Analyst

Dec 2005 - Jan 2008

- Performed project management tasks.
- Organized project Kick-off meeting to explain the requirements to the development team.
- Reviewing content developed by the Instruction Designer team.
- Provided guidance and support to the team members for executing the project.
- Development and review of design and storyboard.

## Element K India Ltd.

#### Designation: Senior Instructional Designer

- Feb 2004 Nov 2005
- Attended conference calls with clients to understand project requirements.
- Developed and delivered training courseware on time and with quality.
- Provided guidance and support to the team members in executing the project.
- Conducted visualization meetings for effective graphical representation of content during the development phase.

# Sify Private Ltd.

## Designation: Media Instructional Designer

Aug 2002 - Feb 2004

- Developed and delivered content as per the project plan with expected quality.
- Conducted collaboration meetings to ensure the content was correctly visualized for effective graphical representation.
- Presented project data in project closeout meetings.

#### SSI Ltd.

# Project Leader

Aug 1997- Aug 2002

- Interacted with clients to define the project requirements, system study & analysis, and defining project deliverables.
- Developed ILTs, WBTs and performed peer reviews.
- Finalized the team members who met the project requirements and provided guidance and support to execute the project.
- Conducted Kick-Off meetings to brief the team on client requirements.
- Managed projects.

# **EDUCATIONAL QUALIFICATIONS**

Bachelor of Electronic Science (BES). 1994 -1997

#### PERSONAL PROFILE

D.O.B : 25.11.1976

MARITAL STATUS : Married

LANGUAGES KNOWN : English, Hindi, Malayalam, and Tamil